It's very important to choose a wedding videographer that can work well with your photographer and vice versa.
Choosing a photographer that works well with your videographer is also important because it can actually ruin a wedding day if a photographer and videographer are not getting along.
So what you want to do is when you, usually people hire their photographers first.
Some people don't, some people go to the videographer first.
But most of it is done through the photographer first.
Ask your photographer for recommendations of who he or she believes that they would work well with.
They might even have people on their website that you can actually click on the links and visit those videographers.
Or they might just have regular people that they always shoot with that they feel comfortable with and they know.
Because typically on a wedding day, what happens is the photographer is the one that should be in control; the one that is screaming out the demands, telling people where to stand, telling people how to pose.
That is the photographer's job.
That's what they were hired to do.
They're hired to get still photography, still photographs.
A videographer's role in a wedding video is to get the candid moments or movement in, during the wedding day.
And so, the videographer is kind of like the second hand person on the actual wedding day, where they're kind of shooting behind the scenes and they?re shooting what the photographer is doing with you on your wedding day.
And so you want to make sure that you don't get a videographer that tries to always jump in and take over everything.
Tries to take over the photographer's role or tries to tell like family, during family group shots, where to stand.
That's just not cool because the photographer, that's what the photographer is hired to do.
Now what we do and probably what you should make sure your videographer does is, we usually wait for the photographer to finish shooting and then he or she will say, hey, do you need to get any shots here.
And we say, yes, we need to get a few shots here.
And we'll go ahead and then we'll do our thing for a couple of minutes and then we move on.
That's working well with a photographer and you want to make sure that your videographer works well with your photographer that way and doesn't try to take over everything.
Because I know a lot of photographers that actually complain about the videographers that they've worked with because that's the how they are and they're always in their shots.
And they're too bossy and they can't get in their shots.
So it's very important to make sure that they work well together.